ELLIAS PALCU

elliaspalcu@gmail.com | 865-724-3444

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER | EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER | WEB-BASED APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Software professional versed in a variety of software engineering forms: embedded software, web-based application engineering, and consultation. Experienced in leading software projects and implementing enterprise-level software solutions in the areas of big data, data analytics/visualization, security, and automation. Full-stack expert, proven in taking software projects from start to finish and understanding all facets of development process: documentation, testing, user experience, database administration, quality assurance, and security. Skilled as a client-facing liaison, capable of navigating through technical requirements while understanding customer needs. Proficient in a multitude of programming languages, operating systems, design architectures, and cloud-based technology.

TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES

- REST APIs
- Automation, Scripting
- Unit, Regression Testing
- Debugging, JTAG
- Troubleshooting
- Test Engineering
- Parallel Programming
- Unix/Linux/Mac OS/Windows
- Hardware Testing
- Embedded Software
- Version Control (Git, SVN)
- Software Design
 Documentation
- RTOS

- Full-Stack Development
- Business Intelligence
- Consulting, Client-Facing
- AWS, Azure
- Project Leading
- Machine Learning
- Data Mining

- Microcontrollers
- Algorithms
- Object-Oriented
- MVC
- IOT
- UI/UX
- Data Structures

EXPERIENCE

INSTRUMENT ENGINEER, TVA; KNOXVILLE, TN

NOV 2017-PRESENT

- Software specialist in group responsible for developing and maintaining control and embedded software for the nuclear siren system across TVA.
- Administrator of version control practices for TVA's IES group.
- Lead application developer integrating full-stack software engineering solutions with modern cloud-based technologies.
- TVA ANS Siren System
 - Software specialist responsible for developing and maintaining control and embedded software for TVA's nuclear sirens
 - o Interface and consult with clients on hardware and software design requirements.
 - o Hardware/Software test and debug dysfunctional and newly fabricated boards.
 - o Develop DOM sheets for new hardware parts per design changes.

Field Reports App

- o Application, utilized by IES, to record job-specific details and house project documentation.
- o Data analytics to visualize man hours, report hours, number of reports throughout any given month/year.
- System description:
 - Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ajax, Bootstrap 3
 - Web Framework: Flask
 - Back-end: MySQL, SQLAlchemy
 - Hosting Service: Azure

EMBEDDED SOFTWARE ENGINEER, EATON; KNOXVILLE, TN

SEP 2016-NOV 2017

- Involved in and lead many IOT product development projects (NDA) pertaining to event-driven firmware development, REST API routing, web-based application development, Python test engineering, and NoSQL database administration.
- **EV-EMCB**
 - Lead test engineer and firmware engineer.
 - Energy management circuit breaker capable of providing power consumption data, remote control of breaker functionality to reduce usage costs, and electric vehicle charging capabilities.
 - o Project in a failing state for **three** years:
 - Inherited at passing 16% (false-positive), and revived project to production at ~99% passing.
 - Now utilized across many utility companies across the United States, such TVA, Duke Energy, and Tesla.

- Software specialist in TVA's IES group.
- Consulted customers on optimal networking, automation, and data acquisition techniques.
- Instrumentation Projects
 - o Programmed and co-authored all instrumentation and documentation for TVA's \$450 million Boone Dam Repair project.
 - o Lead engineer in TVA's \$300,000 initiative in reprogramming all instrumentation across the Tennessee Valley.
 - o Designer of Chickamauga Dam's cost-efficient networking and data acquisition scheme.

SULI COMPUTATIONAL SCIENTIST, ORNL; OAKRIDGE, TN

JUN 2015-AUG 2015

- Internship exposure to data mining, machine learning, and research reporting/documentation.
- Titan Supercomputer Failure Prediction Analysis
 - o Goal: To successfully predict when and where a failure event will occur within system to avoid unnecessary checkpointing.
 - Data Mining: Python
 - o Machine Learning: Python, Sci-Kit Learn, classification/supervised learning algorithms.

LANGUAGES

EDUCATION

MS, Computer Engineering — 3.94 GPA

University of Tennessee, Knoxville 01/2017 - 12/2017

BS, Computer Engineering -3.45 GPA

University of Tennessee, Knoxville 08/2012 - 12/2016

LINKEDIN

http://www.linkedin.com/in/ellias-palcu-64841aa4/

PERSONAL WEBSITE

http://www.aws.epalcu.net

GITHUB

http://www.github.com/epalcu